Edmund B. Chaffee Papers
Edmund B. Chaffee Papers
- Manuscripts
  - Sermons
    - What Can We Do to Prevent It? (Box 63)
    - Was Jesus Insane? (Box 63)
    - What Did Jesus Teach? (Box 63)
    - What Does a Man Need to be Happy? (Box 63)
    - What Evidence is There for the Resurrection of Jesus? (Box 63)
    - What is a Liberal? (Box 63)
    - What is a Christian? (Box 63)
    - What Is This Technocracy? (Box 63)
    - What Makes a Man Great? (Box 63)
    - What One Church Is Doing: Labor Temple (Box 63)
    - What Was Jesus' Idea of Immortality? (Box 64)
    - Who Is Sufficient for These Things? (Box 64)
    - Who Killed Jesus? Who Needs God? (Box 64)
    - Who Was Jesus? (Box 64)
    - Who Was Jesus Christ? (Box 64)
    - Why I Believe in God (Box 64)
    - Why Join the Church? (Box 64)
    - Why Religion? (Box 64)
    - Will America Go Fascist? (Box 64)
    - Will American Capitalism Survive the Present Crisis? (Box 64)
    - Will Science Displace Religion? (Box 64)
    - The Workableness of Non-resistance (Box 64)
    - World Peace and the Recent Election (Box 64)
    - The World We Live In (Box 64)
    - Youth Faces the New Day (Box 64)
    - Untitled, 1914; 1925,; 1926,; undated (Box 64)
    - Incomplete, undated (Box 64)
    - Notes (Box 64)
  - Statements
    - 1916, 1934, undated (Box 64)
  - Manuscripts of Others
    - Unidentified (Box 64)
    - Barnham, Henry D. (Box 64)
    - Chaffee, Margaret Ann, 1933 (Box 64)
    - Clarke, Reverend Merrill (Box 64)
    - Richards, Edward C. M. (Box 64)
    - Thomas, Edward (Box 64)
    - Thomas, Norman (Box 64)
- Diaries
  - 1905-1906 (Box 65)
  - 1908 (Box 65)
  - 1909 (Box 65)
  - 1910 (Box 65)
  - 1911 (Box 66)
  - 1912 (Box 66)
  - 1912 (Box 66)
  - 1912? European Trip (Box 66)
  - 1913-1915 (Box 66)
  - 1918 (Box 66)
  - 1930, European Trip (Box 66)
  - Undated, Canadian Trip (Box 66)
- Notebooks
  - School, 1916 (Box 67)
  - Undated (Orient) (Box 67)
  - 1922 (Box 67)
  - 1925-1926 (Box 67)
  - 1926-1927 (Box 67)
  - 1926-1927 (Box 67)
  - 1928 (Box 67)
  - 1928-1929 (Box 68)
  - 1929-1930 (Box 68)
  - 1930-1931 (Box 68)
  - 1931-1932 (Box 68)
  - 1933-1934 (Box 68)
  - 1933-1934 (Box 68)
  - 1934-1935 (Box 68)
  - Undated (Box 68)
- Photographs
  - Photograph book
    - China (Box 69)
    - Egypt (Box 69)
    - Japan (Box 69)
    - Korea (Box 69)
    - Palestine (Box 69)
    - India (Box 69)
    - Palestine and Trips (Box 70)
  - Photographs
    - Chaffee family (Box 70)
    - Mearns family (Box 70)
    - Others (Box 70)
    - Chaffee family and other subjects (Box 70)
- Scrapbooks
  - 1918-1923 (Box 71)
  - 1918-1924, Newspaper clippings, manuscripts, publications, and material on various subjects (Box 71)
  - 1920, 1929, 1931, 1932 (Box 71)
  - 1921, 1923, 1925, 1927, Newspaper clippings (Box 72)
  - 1924-1926, 1930, 1933, Newspaper clippings (Box 72)
  - 1930, 1932, 1934, Newspaper clippings (Box 72)
- Published material
  - Articles
    - 1917, 1926, 1929 (Box 73)
    - 1930, 1933, 1936 (Box 73)
    - Are Religous Liberals Destructive (Box 73)
    - Christians and War (Box 73)
    - The Church and the Labor Movement (Box 73)
    - The Church and the Social Challenge (Box 73)
    - Communism or Fascism: Must We Choose (Box 73)
    - Communism or Fascism (Box 73)
    - Communism and Religion (Box 73)
    - Critical Mindedness and Its Peril (Box 73)
    - Do Forums, Get Anywhere (Box 73)
    - El Cristianismo: on Movimento del Pueblo (Box 73)
    - Ethics and Propaganda (Box 73)
    - France and the Arabs (Box 73)
    - Is Progress an Illusion (Box 73)
    - The Labor Churches of Canada (Box 73)
    - The Mind of Christ in This Day (Box 73)
    - Partners in Nefarious Traffic (Box 73)
    - Religion and Everyday Life (Box 73)
    - Science Falters (Box 73)
    - Some Conditions in North America That Affect Foreign Missions (Box 74)
    - Some Issues Confronting the Ministry Today (Box 74)
    - Some Thoughts on Humanism (Box 74)
    - The Student Movement in China (Box 74)
    - Son Yat Sen A Chinese Robert Bruce (Box 74)
    - Technocracy’s Stop! Look! Listen! (Box 74)
    - Technocracy's Warning (Box 74)
    - Testing Economic Remedies (Box 74)
    - Unemployment Challenges Religion (Box 74)
    - A Visit to the Home of Tagore (Box 74)
    - What Contributions Has Religion to Make Through the Church for Social Reconstruction (Box 74)
    - What Has Psychical Research Accomplished (Box 74)
    - What Has Religion to do With Economics (Box 74)
    - What Is a Liberal (Box 74)
    - What Is Technocracy (Box 74)
    - What of the Church (Box 74)
    - Unidentified (Box 74)
    - Religion's Voice-Outlook and Independent (column) (Box 74)
    - Special Correspondence for The Christian Century (Box 75)
    - By Others-Various Subjects (Box 75)
  - Books
    - Protestant Churches and the Industrial Crisis, 1933 (Box 75)
  - Books by Others
    - Harriet Martineau, 1932 (Box 75)
    - Raja Yoga, by Swami Vivekananda, 1917 (Box 75)
  - Book Reviews
    - 1934 (Box 76)
    - 1931, 1932 (Box 76)
  - Catalogues, 1936 (Box 76)
  - Letters to the Editor, 1921 (Box 76)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1935; 1936 (Box 76)
  - Newsletters
    - Information Service, 1935; 1936 (Box 76)
    - The Social Service Bulletin, 1930-1934 (Box 76)
    - Newspaper Clippings
      - 1911 (Box 76)
      - 1916, 1924, 1925, 1929, 1932, About Chaffee (Box 76)
      - 1933, 1934, 1936, About Chaffee (Box 76)
      - Undated, About Chaffee (Box 76)
      - 1920, undated, By Chaffee (Box 76)
  - About Others
    - 1916, 1918, 1928, 1929, 1930, 1931 (Box 77)
    - 1932 (Box 77)
    - 1933 (Box 77)
    - 1934 (Box 77)
    - 1935-1936 (Box 77)
    - Undated (Box 77)
    - 1924, 1928, 1932, 1933, 1934 (Labor Temple) (Box 77)
  - Newspapers
    - 1890, 1918 (Box 77)
  - Pamphlets
    - Annual Letter from the "Upper Room," The (Box 77)
    - Give Us Work (Box 77)
    - Meaning of the Evolutionary Process, The (Box 77)
    - By and About Others
      - A-B, 1913; 1920,; 1934-1936 (Box 78)
      - C-E, 1918-1920; 1931-1932 (Box 78)
      - F-G, I-J, L-M, 1888; 1910,; 1918,; 1923,; 1925,; 1933,; 1934 (Box 78)
      - The Labor Temple, January, April, 1930; October 1931,; 1932 (Box 78)
      - N-S, 1902; 1915,; 1920,; 1921,; 1924,; 1925,; 1928,; 1932,; 1934-1936 (Box 78)
      - T-U, W, 1888; 1919,; 1923,; 1928,; 1931-1933,; 1936 (Box 78)
  - Programs and Announcements-Labor Temple
    - 1917-1918, 1922-1927 (Box 78)
    - 1928-1937, undated (Box 79)
  - Reports (Box 79)
  - Reports by Others-Labor Temple Annual Reports, 1921-1929; 1929-1938 (Box 79)
  - Speeches, 1934; 1936 (Box 79)
  - Statements, 1928 (Box 79)
  - Symposiums With Others, 1925; 1933 (Box 79)
  - Proceedings
    - Proceedings of the American Society for Psychical Research
      - 1907? (Box 80)
      - 1907? (Box 80)
      - 1907 (Box 80)
      - 1907-1908 (Box 80)
      - 1908, September (Box 80)
      - 1908, December (Box 81)
      - 1909, July (Box 81)
      - 1909, December (Box 81)
      - 1910, May (Box 81)
      - 1911, April (Box 82)
      - 1911, December (Box 82)
      - 1913, February (Box 82)
      - 1912, May (Box 82)
      - 1913, July (Box 83)
      - 1913, December (Box 83)
      - 1914, July (Box 83)
      - 1914, August (Box 83)
      - 1914, September (Box 83)
      - 1915, August (Box 84)
      - 1916, August (Box 84)
      - 1917, August (Box 85)
      - 1918, June (Box 85)
      - 1919, August (Box 86)
      - 1919, December (Box 86)
      - 1920 (Box 86)
      - 1921 (Box 86)
      - 1924 (Box 87)
      - 1925 (Box 87)
      - 1926 (Box 87)
      - 1927, February (Box 88)
      - 1928, February-June (Box 88)
      - 1929 (Box 89)
      - 1930 (Box 89)
  - Journals
    - Journal of American Society for Psychical Research:
      - 1931 (Box 90)
      - 1931 (Box 90)
      - 1932 (Box 90)
      - 1933, January-June (Box 90)
      - 1933, July-December (Box 91)
      - 1934, January-June (Box 91)
      - 1934, July-December 1935 (Box 91)
      - 1936 (Box 91)
  - Hearings
    - Interstate Migration
      - Part 6, 1940 (Box 92)
      - Part 7, 1940 (Box 92)
      - Part 8, 1940 (Box 92)
      - Part 9, 1940 (Box 92)
      - Part 10, 1941 (Box 92)
    - National Defense Migration
      - First Interim Report, 1941 (Box 92)
      - Part 11, 1941 (Box 93)
      - Part 18, 1941 (Box 93)
      - Part 19, 1941 (Box 93)
      - Part 20, 1941 (Box 93)
      - Part 21, 1941 (Box 93)
      - Part 22, 1941 (Box 93)
      - Part 23, 1941 (Box 94)
      - Part 24, 1941 (Box 94)
      - Third Interim Report, 1942 (Box 94)
      - Part 29, 1942 (Box 94)
      - Part 30, 1942 (Box 94)
      - Part 31, 1942 (Box 94)